emilyslist.org 2006-06-18

# Privacy Policy

**EMILY's List** and **Team EMILY** , a project of EMILY’s List, are committed to protecting the privacy and security of our members and visitors to our website. Outlined below is our online privacy policy for personal information collected through this website and e-mail lists. Please note that EMILY’s List and Team EMILY both contain links to other sites. EMILY’s List and Team EMILY bear no responsibility for the content or privacy practices of such sites. Please take note when you leave our site and review the privacy policies of any site that collects personal or financial information. If you have questions or concerns about these policies, we encourage you to contact us by [clicking here](http://www.emilyslist.org/contact/). 

To unsubscribe from our e-mail updates or change your profile, [click here](http://69.20.85.216/unsub/). 

###  Resale or disclosure of information to third parties 

To process credit card contributions, deliver a personalized experience on our website, and provide information about our activities, EMILY's List and Team EMILY collect some information that can be directly associated with a specific person. We call this "personal information," and it includes names, addresses, telephone numbers, and e-mail addresses. In the case of those who make contributions through the site, it also includes credit card information and the answers to questions which we ask in order to ensure we can legally accept your contribution. 

It is the general policy of EMILY's List and Team EMILY not to make personal information available to anyone other than its employees or agents who need to know that information in the course of their duties. We do not exchange, trade, rent, or give email lists to third parties. 

However, EMILY's List is often required to disclose some personal information to federal, state or local government authorities. For example, federal law requires us to use our best efforts to collect and report the name, mailing address, occupation and name of employer of individuals whose contributions aggregate in excess of $200 in a calendar year. Similarly, when you donate to a candidate through EMILY's List, the law may require us to provide information regarding your donation to the candidates' campaign organizations for reporting purposes. 

We will use your e-mail address to confirm on-line contributions and we may use your phone number and or e-mail address to contact you if we need any additional information about your contribution. We will also use your e-mail address to send you important news and updates from EMILY's List and Team EMILY. If you do not wish to receive these e-mails, please take one of the following actions to request to be unsubscribed: send an email to [information@emilyslist.org](mailto:information@emilyslist.org) and ask to be removed, or send us your full name and email address via United States Mail at 1120 Connecticut Avenue, Ste. 1100, NW, Washington, D.C. 20036. 

###  Browser information collected on the web site 

EMILY's List and Team EMILY analyzes its website logs to constantly improve the value of our website. This includes page views, unique views, unique visitors, repeat visitors, frequency of visits, and peak-volume traffic periods. We do not use our website log files to gather, request, record, require, collect or track any Internet users' personal information. 

We use "cookies" on our site. A "cookie" is a tiny text file that we store on your computer to customize your experience (such as delivering personalized content) and support some necessary functions. We also use cookies to better understand how our visitors use our site. EMILY's List cookies are not shared or revealed to other sites. We do not look at cookies on your machine for other sites. (EMILY's List also makes some use of "web beacons." These are graphical images which allow EMILY's List to understand its visitors' viewing preferences.) 

You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. For more information on how to modify your browser settings to block or filter cookies, see <http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq/>. 

However, if you reject some or all cookies, your experience at our site and on other sites throughout the Internet may not be complete. In addition, if you do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of personalized content delivery offered by EMILY's List or other Internet sites. 

###  Privacy of our e-mail lists 

EMILY's List maintains several e-mail lists to keep EMILY's List members, the press, interested individuals and organizations informed about our activities, breaking news or important events. While we do coordinate our efforts with like-minded websites on a strict opt-in basis, we do not share the e-mail addresses on our lists with outside organizations. EMILY’s List utilizes third party software to manage our e-mail lists. The list server software is configured to refuse to divulge the e-mail addresses of our list subscribers to anyone but authorized EMILY’s List staff or agents. However, EMILY’s List utilizes third party software to manage this data and which uses all viable means to preserve subscribers’ anonymity. 

###  Various Registrations 

In order to use certain features of TeamEMILY.org, an individual may be required to fill out a registration form. During this process a user is required to give their contact information (for example name and e-mail address). This information is used to contact the individual about the tools and activities on our site for which they have expressed interest. If asked for, it is optional for a user to provide demographic information, but recommended so that Team EMILY can provide a more personalized experience on our site. 

###  Surveys 

EMILY’s List uses third party software to send surveys to our members. Our online surveys ask individuals for contact information (such as an e-mail or mailing address). EMILY’s List and Team EMILY use contact data from our surveys to send information about our activities. Other data collected by online surveys is used to educate Team EMILY about the interests and concerns of our members and visitors.  This information is not shared with other organizations. 

###  Tell-A-Friend 

If an individual chooses to use our “Tell-A-Friend” feature to inform friends about EMILY’s List and Team EMILY, we ask for your name and email address, as well as the recipient’s email address. The site sends an automatic, one-time email to the friend inviting them to visit the site and make a contribution. This information is stored for the sole purpose of sending the one-time email. The addresses of the friends you are referring are not added to our lists and they will not be contacted again unless they opt-in to the EMILY’s List or Team EMILY e-mail lists. 

###  Children's privacy 

Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulation establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we have designed our sites to block our knowing acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age-related information is requested. We would remind parents that they have a duty to supervise the Internet activities of their children. 

It is possible that by fraud or deception we may receive information pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent or otherwise delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by emailing us at [information@emilyslist.org](mailto:information@emilyslist.org). 

###  Security 

EMILY's List maintains a variety of physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. For example, we use commercially reasonable tools and techniques to protect against unauthorized access to our systems. Also, we restrict access to personal information to those employees and agents who need to know that information in the course of their duties. We work to protect the security of your personal information when transmitted via our site by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. In addition, we have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss or misuse of information that we have collected from you at our site. 

You should know that EMILY's List has no control over the security of other sites on the Internet you might visit, interact with, or use to make financial transactions. Your own efforts to protect against unauthorized access play an important role in protecting the security of your personal information. You should be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer, and always log out of any site when viewing personal information. Also, we may have links to other, outside websites that we do not control. We are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of these sites. 

###  Changes to this policy 

EMILY's List will revise or update this policy if our practices change, or as we develop better ways to keep you informed about them. You should refer back to this page often for the latest information and the effective date of any changes. If we decide to change this policy, we will post a new policy on our site and change the date at the top. Changes to the policy shall not apply retroactively. 

If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at [information@emilyslist.org](mailto:information@emilyslist.org). You may also reach us via United States Mail at 1120 Connecticut Avenue, NW, Ste. 1100, Washington, DC 20036. 

Changes were made to this policy on March 1, 2005.
